待てよ
Ten.
言葉…　か
The ability to build up a shroud of Nen aura. You can make your body harder,
and considerably slow the effects of aging.
王よ
Zetsu. A technique that nullifies your Nen aura.
自分の名を知りたくはないか？
It is effective for concealing your presence, and recovering from extreme fatigue.
なぜ貴様が 余の名前を知っている？
Ren. A technique to create an
especially strong Nen aura.
フッ。
This ability is crucial for increasing your power.
部下が　お主の 母親の臨終に立ち会ったのよ。
Hatsu. The release of your Nen aura, after boosting via Ren.
いまわの言葉が お主の名だったそうだ。 その部下も護衛軍との戦闘で 死んでしまったかもな。
These four elements are known
as the four major principles, and are critical to the mastery of Nen.
王とネテロが　ついに
For the first time in this fight,
Hisoka has moved!
最後の戦いを 始めようとしていた頃…
And he's smiling ever so slightly.
今も泣き続けていた
What was that about?!
) ((うぅ　俺が…
He's right. By the way, I'm a Transmuter, fickle and dishonest. It fits.
殺る！))
He nailed it.
)
Emitters have short tempers. Specialists are independent.
泣いてる場合か！ パームを捜さなきゃ！
Conjurers are high-strung. Manipulators are argumentative.
なっ！ 倉庫エリアへの扉が 開いてる！
The two of us are quite compatible.
車庫側へ向かう通路の扉も！
Our opposing personalities attract.
何で!?
We could become very intimate.
動くな！ あっ！
But you should take care,
because Transmuters are fickle.
動けば攻撃する。
It takes a mere second for
treasure to turn to trash.
お前にゃ 聞きたいことが山ほどあるが おかしな　そぶりを見せれば
So...
奴が俺に聞きたいこと 決まってる
Do not disappoint me, Gon.
どんなてを使ってでも 聞き出そうとするだろう
He's fast!
んっ？　う…　動くな！ マジで殺すぞ！
Wh-What a strong kick.
ああ　殺せ　願ったりだ！
He sent that stone block flying
all the way to the entrance!
クソ　このガキ！　チクショ！ クソったれが
Fast, fast, fast!
こんな雑魚くせぇ奴に 弱点　突かれるとは！
Hisoka is demonstrating his true power. Critical for Hisoka!
駆け引きが必要な 俺の「ミサイルマン」は
Add points. 3-2!
問答無用で攻撃されると 後手に回るしかねえ！
His nonstop flurry of attacks has been scored as a critical strike.
傷は浅い
He's regained the lead.
フフフ…　じっくりと なぶり殺してやる！
Gon appears to be confused... Does he have no way to fight back?
あっ！　あぁ…！
Amazing... Too amazing.
うっ！　あぁ…！ フフフ…！
Attack me. Forget it.
I'm brainstorming!
うっ！ そいつは 俺の念能力が生み出した生物
I can just barely follow him by eye, but the rest of my body can't keep up.
クロムカデだ。
At this rate, he'll beat the crap out of me!
お前の反抗心を糧に成長する。 うっ！　うぅ…。
Then I'll have to force you
to come over here...
うっ！　あぁ…。
Gon, use Gyo !
俺の命令に背いたり 俺に危害を加えようとすれば
Crap!
最後は体を突き破り　命を奪う！
Do you understand
くっ…。
what is happening?
あっ！　あっ…。
Gon has been drawn toward Hisoka!
いや　待てよ
This is my Elastic Love...
奴が殺意を抱いてくれれば それは最高の反抗心
Also known as Bungee Gum.
恐らく 一瞬にして即死レベルまで
It can expand and contract.
クロムカデは育つ！
And attach and detach as I desire...
安心しろ　殺す気は　ない。
You won't be able to escape.
弾は…　まだ　ある。
Critical and down.
てめぇ　ふざけんなよ!!
6-2!
死ぬぞ！　殺すぞ！
Hisoka hits him with a strong straight right!
あ!!
He turns his aura into a rubbery substance capable of attaching to other objects.
うっ！
Bungee Gum.
フフフ…。
Stand up, Gon... Damn.
フフフ…。 何て　楽！
The score is 6-2. Hisoka increases his lead. Will his undefeated record continue? Stand up, kid!
自分の命と 引き換えのつもりなら
Can you fight? Of course.
何て楽に 引き金を引けることか！
Oh, Gon is standing... But he's sustained significant damage!
うぅ…。
One... When I elbowed you.
分かった！　もう　分かった！ 動かねえよ！
When I was giving you my
aura personality analysis.
降参だ！　頼む　撃つな！
That's dirty!
痛みが和んで 中の生物が苦しんでる？
If I had been using Gyo from the beginning...
負けだ　チクショ。
Now, I have a warning for you.
もう　動けねえ。 ウェルフィンが 負けを認めたから？
Had you been using Gyo, you would have been able to notice my aura, and you could have avoided it
やっぱりだ　クソ…。 いつか　こうなると思ったんだ。
during my aura personality analysis. However, what about situations
one, two, and three?
けどよ…　まさか俺が こんなに　もろいとはよ！
Have you figured it out?
自分の命を全く顧みず 突っ込んで来る奴が
I could have also attached my Bungee Gum
こんなに怖えぇとはよ！
while directly attacking you.
おい。 何だ？
You only need to conceal your aura when you
wish to catch your opponent off guard.
痛みは　マシになったけど この虫　早く取ってくれよ。
Normally, you use your aura while attacking.
チッ　うるせぇな
It doesn't matter if your
opponent sees your aura
こっちは　痛くて それどころじゃねえんだよ！
when you're landing attacks. He's right.
んっ？ んっ？
If I can't dodge Hisoka's attacks, using Gyo to see his aura won't help!
早くしてくれ。
This is bad.
少し　待ってくれ！
His power's far more difficult to
handle than I expected!
俺の「ミサイルマン」に 解除の方法なんてねえんだよ
So you have to dodge all of Hisoka's attacks
けど　それを バカ正直に言ったら　ヤベェ
if you want to avoid his Bungee Gum.
クソ！ どうやって乗り切る!?
But if you're able to defend...
時間を稼ぐんだ 何か名案が浮かぶまで
Even if you block, he can still attach
his aura to the part you block with.
うっ！　痛みで意識が
I can't escape. What should I do?
かすん…　で…。
Okay, that's enough talk. Let us prepare for battle.
ウソ！　ウソ！　もう　しねえよ！
Gon...
それじゃ　早くこれを取れ。
Gon!
あっ　その…　だから　その…。
Good... You're so good.
はぁ？
Those eyes.
解除できねえんだよ！ 一度　撃っちまうと　もう。
I can't wait
だから　言えなかった 本当だ！　信じてくれよ！
to break you.
まただ…　苦しんでる
But not yet...
しょうがねえだろ。
More...
どうせ 殺すつもりで攻撃するんだ。
More! Until I can no longer bear to ruin you.
後のことなんか知るか！
Rush! Rush! Rush! Rush!
…って　相手の都合なんざ 全く考えなかったからな。
Once you've matured... Rush! Rush! Rush! Rush!
フッ　念能力とは よく言ったもんだぜ。
Until you've reached soaring new heights... I must wait.
俺の性格 そのまんま反映してやがる。
A vicious rush!
俺の性格？　奴の本音
Oh, not again!
ウェルフィン。 んっ？ 何を聞く？　俺が聞きたいこと
Hisoka draws Gon into another
punch from his left fist!
こいつと似た奴を知ってる
Good.
お前　人間だった頃の 記憶は　あるか？
I managed to block that! I'm getting used to being dragged
around by his Bungee Gum.
何だよ　急に。
This isn't over.
覚えてねえな。
It's not over yet!
ウソだな。 うわっ！　何？　何？　やめろよ！ 待てって！　落ち着け！
But if I let my fear overcome me, I'll never be able to beat anyone else!
正直に話さないと　撃つ！
Critical for both sides! Plus two points!
うっ。
Plus a knockdown for Hisoka!
うぅ…。
What? Total scores are now 9 points for Hisoka,
and 4 points for Gon!
目が覚めた時
I even blocked his attack! What? Something's wrong with this ref!
最初に思ったのは…。
Are you blind?
「チクショ まだ覚えてやがった」だ。
In response to the ref's decision, the crowd has filled the arena with boos. Fight!
)
If he gets ten points, I lose. I only have one point left.
ＮＧＬで 虫の化け物に殺されたはず。
He doesn't need to knock me down. If I get hit by any attack, it's over!
一番…
I meant my right.
一番　忘れたかったことは しっかり覚えてた。
Down, and clean hit! Plus two points.
首を絞める父親と
The winner, by, TKO, is... Hisoka!
背後で見てる女。
Huh?
助けてくれたのは
While you were complaining to the referee, I sent the aura on my left hand to the stone.
血のつながってない弟だった。
Total scores are now 9 points for Hisoka,
and 4 points for Gon!
思い出した！ すげぇ　似てたんだ　ジャイロに。
Then I immediately activated Bungee Gum.
あいつとは　よく　不幸自慢したな。
It's really over? You've made incredible progress.
泣いた日を 笑って話し合えるのは
But you lack experience.
あいつだけだった。
About ten more fights, and you
should stand a better chance.
あいつも俺も　空っぽで…。 だから何も　隠さずに済んだ。
If we're in Heavens Arena, at least. Therefore, I will not fight you here again.
何してんだろ？　あいつ。
Next time, we'll fight in the real world,
without any rules to restrain us.
そうだ ジャイロに会えりゃ　それでいい。
With this victory, Hisoka has
earned his tenth win
アリとか　人とか
and the right to challenge a Floor Master!
金とか国とか　面倒くせぇや。
Gon has fought bravely, and we wish
him the best in his next match.
行けよ　虫は消えたぜ。
This is your commentator, Cocco, signing off! A referee is supposed to be completely impartial.
お前は　まだ　やることあんだろ？
But given today's matchup, I thought it prudent
通路の扉を開けたのは　何でだ？ んっ？　あぁ
to end the fight as quickly as possible, even if it meant lowering my standards.
奥のお宝目的の 雑魚どもを行かせただけだ。
So he's a technical ref. What does that mean? If a ref believes that a
fight may get dangerous, he'll award points like crazy, to finish it quickly.
モニターでブロウとお前を見て
You have to take that into
consideration when placing a bet.
お前が戻るタイミングで あいつらを行かせた。
Man, I was certain that Hisoka would win 10-0...
)
I have nothing to say to you
about the fight with Hisoka.
) ) そんだけだ。
You were the one fighting him,
so I'm sure you understand best of all.
) ブロウを 撃てなかったお前を見て
Understand what? What he learned from that fight. Yes!
くみしやすしと思ったのが
Gon, what did you learn? A secret.
とんだ誤算だったぜ。
Gon-kun, Killua-kun...
もう行けよ　俺は疲れた。
You will need to master
your own styles of Nen, as you continue down your chosen paths.
最後に　一つ。 んっ？ 宮殿で　女の人を見たか？
Yes! Yeah. I'm glad I was able to meet you.
女？　…か　どうか知らねえが
You've set a worthy mark for me to surpass! You think you can pass us?
護衛軍に捕まって 繭にされた人間が一人いたな。
One day, for sure! Won't happen. I can't wait to see you do it, Zushi. Osu!
その人は　どこにいる？
Well, let's go.
エレベーター上がって左側。
Yeah. Thank you for everything, Wing-san!
突き当たりの部屋だ。
Yeah, same here.
奴らは「１号」って呼んでた。
Thank you. Take care, you two.
サンキュー。
Zushi, until we meet again!
アハハハハ。
Osu!
正直に話すって 楽だなって思ってよ。
Well, you finally accomplished
your objective, right? Uh-huh. Then we don't have any more business here.
他人を　そして
Gon, what are you going to do? Go back to Whale Island.
自分をも信じられずに 生きて来たウェルフィン
Whale Island? Uh-huh.
そんな彼が　初めて 心を開いて告げた真実こそ
I was able to return the favor to Hisoka, so I want to go back to the island,
and show Mito-san my license.
イカルゴが探し求めていた人の 居場所だった
It's been over half a year since I left...